I'm going to transform my voice into a
violin.
>> [music]
>> Welcome back to the channel. I'm Audrey
and in this video we'll cover recording
[music] with Studio 2.0. So you'll gain
the skills you need to capture clean,
high-quality audio. This is important
because whether you're using your
recordings in their original state
[music] in your music or as reference
points for Suno to turn them into
something magical, [music]
there's some best practices that will
set you up for success. Let's dive in.
Recording audio in Suno Studio is not
new, but it's still one of the most
inspirational ways to work because it
allows you to capture live audio to use
in your music. This is a pretty standard
DAW feature where you can record every
layer from scratch, but the Suno
difference is that you can use any audio
as a source for generating new sounds.
What this means is you don't need to be
a great singer or play an instrument at
a professional level.
>> [music]
>> You can sing out of key, you can tap on
your desk, record it into Studio, and
prompt Suno to transform it into
something different. I'm going to show
you how to record in just a second, but
first just to give you an idea of some
of the power that Studio has, I'm going
to transform my voice into a violin.
Let's start with capturing your audio.
You can actually record up to two
sources of audio at the same time in
Studio, but for the purposes of this
demo, I'm just going to record one
channel, my voice into this mic which is
connected to my computer. If the
internal mic on your computer is all you
have, it'll be fine, but if you have an
external mic connected via a USB or an
audio interface, it's going to be a much
higher quality result. I'm going to open
up a song I've been working on in the
studio. I've got all of the instrumental
tracks, but I want to add some vocals.
First, I need to add a new track, so
I'll either click add new track on the
bottom left or I can press shift T and
then the letter A for audio. Here's a
tip, I'm going to rename my track vocal
one to stay organized. Now you want to
set your input source. You select that
from the drop down and because I have a
gain control on my mic, I'm going to do
a test to set the level so that I don't
clip the input. Now we've set our input
to input B, which is the external mic,
so I'm going to click on B to arm my
track and we're ready to record now. I'm
going to wear headphones so the mic
doesn't pick up the track while
recording and I'm using wired headphones
so that there is no latency between what
I'm hearing and what I'm recording. And
make sure you're in a quiet space when
you record so your mic doesn't pick up
any background noise. Right before we
start recording, we want to actually
calibrate the latency. This is super
important to make sure that everything
you record is perfectly aligned with the
rest of your track. Super easy to do,
just go to the drop down below the red
record button and then click calibrate
next to latency and you're going to hear
some taps. That's just Studio
calculating the latency to make sure
everything's lined up. The final thing I
want to do is turn on the metronome so I
have a timing reference during the take.
So I'll either click on the metronome
button on the top or I'll press shift C.
Drop the playhead where you want to
start recording and then click the
record button or press shift R to start
the recording. Studio will be recording
and you'll see the audio coming into new
clips on your audio tracks. All right,
I'm going to sing now.
>> Here we are
somewhere way above the clouds
like the gravity
can't hold [screaming]
us down.
Our world
stands stand still.
It's just you and me.
Floating
in the ecstasy.
Woo!
There are two pro features that I
haven't mentioned yet, and those are
pre-roll and count-in, which can be
accessed from a small drop-down under
the main record button. Pre-roll starts
the playhead rolling one, two, or four
bars before the playhead, so you can
preview your track in regular playback
before the track starts recording. This
is great if you're overdubbing or
dropping in takes onto your timeline,
which is a classic studio technique.
Count-in lets you hear the metronome for
one, two, or four bars before your
recording starts, so you can lock in
your timing for the upcoming take. This
is great if you don't want to hear the
metronome during your recording take.
Maybe it's distracting, or you want to
focus on walking into another
instrument, but you need that tempo
reference before you start rolling.
When recording, it's really common to
compile [music] a great vocal
performance out of many different takes.
We call this comping, and here's how to
do it. So, you can see I have two
different takes of this vocal, and I can
just select the best part of each vocal
take to put it onto my comped vocal
track. I will solo this first one. Let's
hear the first line.
>> Here we are.
>> And then, maybe we'll hear the second
line.
>> Here we are.
>> I like the first take better, so I'm
going to just select that first take to
put it on my comp track.
All right, and we'll keep going. Let's
see what the next line sounds like with
vocal take one.
>> Somewhere way above the clouds.
>> Okay, let's listen to the second take.
>> Ooh, I love that second take, so let me
just select the segment of that second
take and put that on my comp track. So,
for this one, I actually like the first
half of the second take on this line,
but I like the word gravity better on my
first take. So, I'm just going to take
that word gravity from take one, and
then I want to smooth out the edges by
adding some clip fades, which I can do
using either the fade icon or pressing
shift F. You can add some track effects
by clicking the add track effects
button, where you can add reverb, a
compressor, EQ, whatever you want.
There's another video that goes into
more detail about that. Okay, that's all
for this video. You may have noticed
that I didn't [music] cover recording
MIDI. Don't worry, there's another video
on our channel where I cover that in
depth. Leave us a comment below letting
us know what you're most excited for in
Studio 2.0, and thanks for watching.
>> Hello.
Hello.
>> [music]
>> Hello.